## **Summary**

Innovative Sr. UI/UX Designer and Sr. Graphic Designer with over 15 years of experience creating exceptional user-friendly experiences and visual designs. Managing multiple projects simultaneously and meeting tight deadlines. Excellent communication skills, building positive relationships with internal and external customers.

## **Experience**

**BenefitHub** - Tampa, Florida - July 2015 - October 2024 UX Designer II, UI/UX Developer II

- Rendered mockups for BenefitHub's Employee Perks and Discount Platform to promote a great user experience
- Generated low & high-fidelity prototypes and wireframes in Adobe XD or Figma to showcase design concepts
- Produced sitemaps, journey maps and user flows with tools like Miro and Visio to structure user experience
- Designed landing pages, web apps, modules, widgets, content pages, and more for ultimate user engagement
- Created logos, vector graphics, icons, ads, product cards and other graphic elements for website enhancement
- Finalized and optimized graphic elements and image assets for handoff to developers for implementation
- Built Adobe libraries and design systems replicating a UI Kit comprised of React.js components such as buttons, modals, input fields, navigation, icons, and style libraries for fonts, color themes, etc. for design consistency
- Developed responsive, mobile-first products with HTML5, CSS3, SASS, and JavaScript to satisfy requirements
- Partnered with front-end and back-end developers for precision and on-time deliverables
- Inspected development projects with cross-browser testing across multiple devices for utmost accuracy
- Complied with WCAG web accessibility standards to ensure designs maintained optimal compatibility
- Collaborated with team members using email, Slack, Teams and Zoom for effective communication
- Utilized Jira and monday.com for product lifecycle management to enhance team coordination
- Managed project timelines, resources and deliverables for multiple UX design initiatives ensuring seamless integration of user research, prototyping, and testing phases

## **Raymond James Financial** - St. Petersburg, Florida - February 2015 - June 2015 **Web Admin Contractor**

- Constructed websites with Sitecore CMS, HTML and CSS producing high conversion rates for financial officers
- Designed logos, graphics and web banners, resulting in creative brand consistency throughout the site
- Refined images with color correction and other adjustments ensuring photos aligned with brand's aesthetics
- Cropped and tailored images for various platforms and devices, ensuring visual appeal for all device sizes
- Optimized images improving page load speed, boosting website's SEO ranking and improving user experience

# **Sign-Age of Tampa Bay** - Clearwater, Florida - August 2011 - June 2014 **Senior Graphic Designer and Web Assistant**

- Updated company's website content and product image gallery using Firespring CMS to increase engagement
- Designed various signs, banners, indoor/outdoor architectural signs, trade show displays, vehicle wraps, wall murals, POP, and more, while adhering to ADA standards and achieving high customer satisfaction
- Prepared art files for wide-format printing and outsourcing to vendors resulting in ultimate print quality
- Produced 3D-sign technical drawings that ensured city and county contract approvals needed for construction

**Tampa Print Services** - Tampa, Florida - April 2003 - March 2011 **Pre-Press Manager and Sr. Graphic Designer** 

- Managed the pre-press dept., ensuring the press and digital depts. produced maximum quality products
- Designed logos, brochures, flyers, postcards and other B2B and B2C marketing materials for various clients
- Handled design, pre-press and software updates to stay on schedule and ensure deadlines were met
- Prepared art files for offset, flexographic, wide-format and digital printing for optimized printed materials

**Freelance & Contract Work** - St. Petersburg, Florida - January 2010 - December 2022 **Graphic Designer and UI/UX Designer and Developer** 

- Create, update and develop landing pages, forms, content pages, and more for various websites
- Design logos, brochures, postcards, flyers, signs, package designs, album covers, trade show pieces, emails, board game, static and motion graphic social media ads, and more for various clients' marketing initiatives
- Produce motion graphic videos, music lyric videos and social media pieces to boost sales and engagement
- Enhance imagery and optimize photos for print and web to gain excitement of products and attract end users

### **Education**

**St. Petersburg College** - St. Petersburg, Florida Associate of Science - Computer Science, Web Development

**Coding Dojo Web Development Boot Camp** - Mountain View, California **Web development boot camp** 

**Academy of Creative Arts College of Design** - Cincinnati, Ohio Associate of Arts - Commercial Art

### **Skills and Tools**

Adobe Creative Cloud, Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Acrobat, Adobe Audition, Adobe After Effects, Adobe Dreamweaver, Microsoft Office Suite, Microsoft 365, CoPilot, Google Suite, Google Docs, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Figma, Miro, Visio, Sitecore CMS, Firespring CMS, WordPress, Wix, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, JSON, Media Queries, GitHub, Azure DevOps, Jira, UI/UX Design, Graphic Design, Web Design, Visual Design, Brand Design, Multi-Media Design, Pre-Press, Vector Art, Prototyping, Wireframing, Art Production, Front-End Development, Mobile-First Development, monday.com, Zoom, Slack, Teams, A/B Testing, UX Research, Cross-Browser Testing, Copywriting, Copy Editing, Photo Editing, Die Line Drawing, Technical Drawing, Technical Writing, ADA Compliance, WCAG Web Accessibility, Scrum, Agile, Waterfall, Kanban, Project Management, Design Systems